firstflight.net 2016-03-14

# First Flight Couriers Ltd.

**Protection of Customer Information** We understand the importance of privacy to our customers and visitors to FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED web sites.  For many years, our policy has been to treat what we learn about our customers as confidential.  For example, we will not give or sell confidential or Personal Information (as described below) about our customer to any third party not affiliated with their transaction, except as required by law or as necessary to provide FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED services to the customer.

We collect and store information about every package we handle so that we can efficiently provide the package delivery services demanded by our customers.  We use information about our customers, their packages, and their shipping activity to provide or enhance the services we make available to our customers, communicate with our customers about additional services they may find of value, satisfy our legitimate business interests (including performing trend analysis and market studies), set prices, establish credit, fulfill a Contract of Carriage or Service Agreement, accomplish the billing function, and comply with government regulations.  Although government regulations vary in the many countries in which we operate, they frequently include the reporting of information to transportation, safety, customs, and other regulatory agencies.

As we collect and use information about our customers, we may contract with vendors to assist us in processing that information for those purposes listed in the previous paragraph.  These vendors are required to maintain the confidentiality of the information and are restricted from using the information for any other purpose.  In addition, as FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED continues to develop its business, we may buy or sell subsidiaries or business units.  As part of these transactions, customer information of the subsidiaries or business units may be one of the transferred assets. 

Some of the information collected by FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED is data which relates to an identifiable person ("Personal Information").  Examples of Personal Information are names, addresses, e-mail addresses, credit card numbers and telephone numbers.  We never sell information to third parties that could be used to specifically identify an individual customer or group of customers.  Anonym zed data, with all names, addresses and other Personal Information removed, is sometimes shared with third parties.  Finally, we do provide Personal Information to government agencies as required by law or regulation.

In addition to the uses of the information described in the paragraphs above, we collect telephone numbers and e-mail addresses in the event that we have to contact the shipper, or the shipment recipient or addressee, to resolve a question or provide shipment status information.

**Shipment Information**

Information, including Personal Information, provided as part of a shipping transaction represents a record of that business transaction and cannot be altered after the transaction is complete except as provided in the FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED Terms and Conditions.  Although we make reasonable efforts to limit access to our facilities and vehicles to authorized personnel, we are not responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of information that is printed and placed in plain view on a package or letter.

**Security and Integrity of Information**

We treat our data as assets that must be protected against loss and unauthorized access.  We employ information security techniques to appropriately protect confidential information from unauthorized access by users inside and outside the company.  Access to customer information is limited to those employees who have a legitimate business need for that information.

FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED Web Sites, and their supporting systems, employ generally accepted information security techniques such as firewalls, access control procedures and cryptography to appropriately protect confidential information from unauthorized access.

**Retention of Customer Information**

We retain information, including Personal Information, about customers as necessary for business purposes and as required by government regulation.  For example, we retain information about packages, including names and addresses, so that we can provide proof of delivery information and to process claim requests.  We carefully dispose of records and delete information when retention periods expire.

**Customers are Responsible for Protecting Information and Systems on Their Premises**

Some information about FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED customers and their packages is stored in shipping systems located on customer premises.  Customers concerned about the security of their information in these systems should secure it by activating passwords and using physical access controls.  When these systems (hardware or software) are provided by FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED, we provide tools to facilitate customer efforts to safeguard their information. 

**The FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED Web Sites**

The following paragraphs describe our commitment to the protection of Personal Information as it applies to the FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED Web Sites, which are web sites controlled or operated by a FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED entity (such as a FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED business unit) or a FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED affiliate, unless the web site expressly publishes a different or modified privacy policy.

**What Information We Collect And How We Will Use It**

Users can visit most areas of the FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED Web Sites without revealing who they are or providing any information about themselves.  However, some of our interactive services require that users identify themselves in order to enable the interactive function.  We may ask users to provide some Personal Information in these situations.

**Links to Other Sites**

FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED provides links to external sites as a convenience to the user.  The inclusion of any link does not imply FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED endorsement of the external site company, its web site, or the products and services it promotes and sells.  FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites.

**Cookies**

Cookies are small text files that a web site can send to a user's browser for storage on the hard drive.  Cookies can make use of the web easier by saving and administering status, application, preferences and other user information.  Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies but users can change the setting to refuse cookies or to be alerted when cookies are being sent. For instructions on how to change cookie settings, look in the Help menu on your Internet browser.  Although refusal of cookies will not interfere with the ability to interact with the FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED Web Sites, users will need to accept cookies in order to use certain functionality (for example, My FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED) provided at the FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED Web Sites.

We use cookies (sometimes in conjunction with other technology) (i) to keep track of and administer customer status, preferences, business information and other information provided by a user, (ii) for security purposes, and (iii) to understand visitor usage of the FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED Web Sites on an anonymous basis.

Other than cookies used in connection with registered users of a FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED Web Site or used to transfer information from one application to another on one or more of the FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED Web Sites, information collected by cookies used in connection with the FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED Web Sites is not used by FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED to identify an individual.  My FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED cookies are placed every time a user logs in and are available for that session only.  Cookies used to transfer information from one application to another are available only in the session of that transfer.  Other cookies are stored indefinitely on users' hard drives.

**Web Surveys**

From time to time, we include survey forms on the FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED Web Sites to better understand our customers' needs and to create web sites that respond to their interests.  Customers may opt-out of participating in follow-up surveys.  FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED will not disclose survey response information to companies or individuals outside FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED with two exceptions: 

  1. Anonymized data, with all names, addresses and other personally identifiable information removed. 
  2. To vendors who are required to maintain the confidentiality of the information and are restricted from using the information for any purpose other than helping to provide services to FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED or FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED customers. 

**FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED Web Site Applications**

Users of FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED Internet Shipping and other applications on the FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED Web Sites that enable the purchase of products and services who choose to use credit cards for payment are required to provide information about themselves and their card.  We use this information to establish credit for billing.  
  
**IP Addresses**

The FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED Web Sites collect IP addresses for system administration, security, and statistical analysis purposes.  An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to a computer whenever it is connected to the Internet.  We log these addresses and analyze them to understand where requests originate so that we can provide the most efficient service, enhance security, ensure appropriate usage and produce traffic volume statistics. 

**Assent**

Your continued use of this site signifies your assent to the FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED Privacy Policy.  We reserve the right, at our discretion, to modify, add, or remove portions of this policy at any time by posting the revised policy at the FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED Web Sites.  Please check this page periodically for changes.

**Contacting FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED**

If you have questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your experience on any of the FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED Web Sites, you can contact: **_[**ffcl@firstflight.net**](mailto:ffcl@firstflight.net)_.**

Comments, suggestions or materials sent or transmitted to FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED shall be deemed to be non-confidential.  FIRST FLIGHT COURIERS LIMITED shall have no obligation of any kind with respect to such comments, suggestions or materials and shall be free to use and distribute them to others without limitation, including, but not limited to developing and marketing products incorporating them.
